JÜRGEN BRANDSTETTER

SKILLS

Team

Team Lead · Project Management ·

People Development

Tech

Typescript · React · Node · PostgreSQL ·

Firebase · Cloud-Functions · Material UI ·

OpenAI-API · Next

EDUCATION

PhD, Human Interface Technology

University of Oxford (UK), University of Canterbury (NZ)

01/2013 - 12/2016

MSc, Media Informatics

Vienna Institute of Technology (AT), University of Copenhagen (DK)

01/2011 - 12/2012

BSc, Computer Science

Vienna Institute of Technology (AT)

01/2007 - 12/2011

Engineer, Electronic and Computer Science

HTBLA-Steyr (AT)

01/2001 - 12/2006

LANGUAGES

German	Native	••••
English	Native	•••••
Arabic	Beginner	••••

Founding Engineer / Product Manager / CTO

📞 +43 650 / 2379275 🔘 j@brandstetter.io 🕜 brandstetter.io

Value Linz, Austria, EU

SUMMARY

With more than 10 years of experience as a founding engineer, I'm accustomed to wearing many hats. I manage and develop the product's underlying software architecture and its UX by working closely with the customer. Communication skills are a cornerstone of my role, enabling me to effectively translate complex technical concepts between cross-functional teams and customers/C-Level/Board. When it comes to the technical team, I oversee the development process, write code reviews, draft job offers, conduct interviews, provide constructive performance reviews, and mentor them to become seniors in their roles. Most importantly, I don't shy away from uncomfortable or complex conversations, employing an empathetic approach.

EXPERIENCE

Founding Engineer / Co-Founder (CTO)

2016 - Present Auckland, NZ

amy.app

. . .

• My job is to lead the development of our Al-driven maths tutor.

Visiting Researcher

06/2014 - 10/2014

Microsoft Research (Fuse Lab HRI/HCI)

Manhattan, NYC, USA

Microsoft's Research Arm

Personal Al Maths Tutor

 I worked on persuasive robotic technology. The goal was to motivate co-workers to stand or walk at least once an hour.

Android and Web Developer

07/2012 - 02/2013

OpenResearch

Vienna, Austria, EU

App Development Agency

• I worked on the software architecture of various project the agency developed.

Android Developer

09/2010 - 02/2011 Vienna, Austria, EU

OpenResearch

App Development Agency

- I worked on Cluster Algorithms for Maps Views.
- I worked on the ÖAMTC-Android App.

Product Manager

04/2007 - 09/2007

A-K-D Wohnservice GmbH

Pregarten, Austria, EU

Interior Design and Production

• I created the companies internal project tracking system.

Founding Engineer / Co-Founder

01/2004 - 12/2010

EU

WER ist IN

Reichenstein, Austria,

Online company register similar to the yellow pages but on Maps

 As a founding engineer I worked on the technical side as well as on customer support, sales and UX.